{
    "id": "8af66d2981734e3d9730dcbe5fafd095",
    "title": "Kinds Of Subordinate Clauses Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "ce0b3fa2cdf64547907360a289bb2a2d",
            "title": "Kinds Of Subordinate Clauses Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What she said made me angry.",
                    "description": "Here what she said is the subject of the verb made hence, it is a noun clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I donâ€™t know what I am supposed to do.",
                    "description": "Here what I am supposed to do is the object of the verb know hence, it is a noun clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I know a man who deals in antique furniture.",
                    "description": "Here who deals in antique furniture modifies the noun man hence, it is an adjective clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She asked me what I was doing there.",
                    "description": "Here what I was doing there is the direct object of the verb asked hence, it is a noun clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I love him because he is my brother.",
                    "description": "Because he is my brother is an adverb clause of reason.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "As soon as the bus arrived, the children rushed to board it.",
                    "description": "As soon as the bus arrived is an adverb clause of reason.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Though I had a headache, I enjoyed the movie.",
                    "description": "Though I had a headache is an adverb clause of concession or contrast.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "How they escaped is a mystery.",
                    "description": "How they escaped is the subject of the verb is hence, it is a noun clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "All that I have is yours.",
                    "description": "That I have modifies the pronoun all hence, it is an adjective clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She married an engineer whom she met on a bus.",
                    "description": "Whom she met on a bus is an adjective clause modifying the noun engineer. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "All that glitters is not gold.",
                    "description": "That glitters is an adjective clause modifying all. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Noun clause",
                        "Adjective clause",
                        "Adverb clause"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}